Anders G. Nordby



Motzfeldtsgate 14, N-0187 Oslo, NORWAY (+47) 932 20 333 anders@delichon.no

http://delichon.no/services/anders/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/agnordby/

DESCRIPTION

Anders is a systems architect and senior developer with customer focus and many years of experience from the industry. He has delivered portals and publishing solutions in both private and public sector, having had responsibility for both functional and non-functional requirements.

Anders is a certified project manager with the **PRINCE2 Foundation** certification. He is also a **Certified Scrum Master**, and has had the role of *scrum master* in several projects.

Anders often participates in the projects from an early phase, and contributes to the solution architecture, handling of requirements and estimation. As a senior developer, Anders primarily works backend, for instance with integrations, but he also has some experience with *Javascript* frontend frameworks like *Knockout*, *Angular* and *React*.

Anders has experience as a teacher, which is useful when technical challenges are to be explained in a non-technical and jargon-free manner. He has also been mentor for new employees.

RELEVANT PROJECT EXPERIENCE

04.20I8 - 08.20I8 (SOPRA STERIA)

Norwegian Tax Administration: Intranet Senior Developer / Architect

Anders worked with maintenance, development and documentation on an existing intranet solution called "the SKO portal". The solution was based on *Episerver CMS*. Anders contributed with training for the internal employees, and he created a set of recipes for simplifying the editors' daily work.

Some of the tools and technologies Anders used in this project were: *Episerver CMS, Microsoft .Net, C#, Microsoft SQL Server, Ajax, Javascript, Jira, Confluence, Git, Octopus Deploy.*

05.2016 - 08.2017 (cgi)

ASKO: Better Selling Commerce Website *Senior Developer*

ASKO is Norway's largest grocery wholesale, and the project aimed at creating a new B2B portal that would be both more user friendly and also selling more products through better recommendations.

Anders was responsible for installing the *inRiver PIM* system into the solution, optimizing it and develop integrations between the *inRiver PIM* system and the customer's various internal systems. He was also responsible for performance testing of the solution using *jMeter* and *Blazemeter*. Anders developed an authentication system based on *IdentityServer3* for handling logins.

Some of the tools and technologies Anders used in this project were: Episerver CMS, Episerver Commerce, inRiver PIM, Microsoft .Net, C#, Microsoft SQL Server, REST Services, PowerShell, WebAPI, WCF, IdentityServer3, Jira, Confluence, TFS, Git, Octopus Deploy.

KEY COMPETENCIES

Processes

 \subseteq

Systems Architecture, Scrum, Kanban, Project Management.

Development

Episerver CMS, Episerver Commerce, Episerver Find, C#, ASP.Net, MVC, Apptus eSales, inRiver PIM, IdentityServer, T-SQL, PL/SQL, JavaScript, JSON, Ajax, NServiceBus, WCF, WebServices, REST, WebAPI, XML, HTML, CSS, jQuery, PowerShell, LATEX.

Tools

Jira, Confluence, Git, TFS, SubVersion, ReSharper, NewRelic, jMeter, BlazeMeter, NuGet.

CERTIFICATIONS

2019 **PRINCE2 Practitioner**PeopleCert

2019 **Certified Scrum Master**Scrum Alliance

2018 PRINCE2 Foundation PeopleCert

2018 Programming HTML5 with Javascript & CSS3
Microsoft

2017 Certified Episerver Developer Episerver

2016 Certified inRiver Developer inRiver

COURSES

2019 PRINCE2 Practitioner

Metier OEC

2019 Certified Scrum Master Course Glasspaper

2019 Architecture Engineering Workshop
Tom Gilb

2018 Software Architechture School Sopra Steria

2016 inRiver Certified Developer inRiver

2015 Lead Enterprise Architect Programme (LEAP)

Microsoft

Fellesforbundet: New Public Website

Senior Developer, Team Lead, Scrum Master, Mentor

Fellesforbundet is one of Norway's largest trade unions.

Anders was responsible for planning and estimation of the solution, and also for coordinating the work between the developers on the team, and for keeping the customer updated about the progress. Anders participated hands-on in development of the solution, which was based on textitEpiserver CMS.

One of the developers came straight from college, and Anders was assigned the role as mentor, teaching the new employee about Episerver CMS and also about the various internal systems at CGI.

Some of the tools and technologies Anders used in this project were: Episerver CMS, Microsoft .Net, C#, Microsoft SQL Server, REST Services, PowerShell, WebAPI, Jira, Confluence, TFS, Octopus Deploy.

03.20I4 - 05.20I5 (CGI)

Tekna: New Public Website Senior Developer, Team Lead

Tekna is a trade union for technical and scientific professionals.

The project consisted of two sub projects, a CMS-project and a CRM-project. Anders was responsible for planning, estimation and coordination among the CMS developers. As a developer, Anders was responsible for the integration between the CMS and CRM projects.

Some of the tools and technologies Anders used in this project were: Episerver CMS, Microsoft .Net, C#, Microsoft SQL Server, REST Services, PowerShell, WebAPI, Jira, Confluence, TFS, Octopus Deploy, NServiceBus, Knockout.js, Javascript, jQuery.

08.2012 - 03.2014 (Making Waves)

Stortinget: New Intranet Senior Developer, Mentor

Anders was responsible for creating a solution gathering calendar events from some 30-odd calendars, letting end-users find their calendar information in a single place. He also was responsible for integrating Episerver CMS with the IntelliSearch search engine, and also for the integration between the new Episerver CMS solution and the Sharepoint solution that was developed in parallel.

During the project, Anders also fulfilled the role as mentor for two new employees.

Some of the tools and technologies Anders used in this project were: Episerver CMS, Microsoft .Net, C#, Microsoft SQL Server, REST Services, PowerShell, IntelliSearch, TFS, Octopus Deploy, Making Waves ActivityFeed, Knockout.js, Javascript, jQuery, Jira, Confluence.

02.20IO - 03.20II (TARANTELL)

Synoptik: New public websites for Brilleland & Interoptik Senior Developer, Team Lead, Scrum Master

Anders was responsible for the planning and development of two new web solutions based on Episerver CMS, but with as much code re-use as possible to keep the costs down.

Some of the tools and technologies Anders used in this project were: Episerver CMS, Microsoft .Net, C#, Microsoft SQL Server, PowerShell, TFS, Octopus Deploy, Javascript, ¡Query, FlusterMaps, Google Mini, Jira, Confluence.

EDUCATION

Secondary Education Teacher Training 2003 - 2004 BACHELOR'S DEGREE ADDITIONAL COURSES University of Oslo IT Candidate 1999 - 2000 Object Oriented Programming. The Business Academy, Oslo Candidatus Magisterii 1987 – 1996 OLD GRADE BETWEEN BACHELOR AND MASTER

Mathematics, Computer Science, Japanese. University of Oslo

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Systems Architect & Senior Developer 05.2019 - PRESENT Delichon **Daily Manager** 05.2019 - PRESENT Delichon Lead Software Engineer 01.2018 - 04.2019 Sopra Steria Senior Web Developer 03.2014 - 08.2017 **Senior Systems Consultant** 03.2010 - 02.2014 TARANTELL MERGED WITH MAKING WAVES Making Waves / Tarantell 08.2008 - 12.2009 Consultant / Systems Developer Creuna 02.2006 - 07.2008 Systems Developer & Project Manager INFOFINDER BOUGHT OCELLUZ InfoFinder / Ocelluz **Self Employed** 10.2004 - 02.2008 Anders Nordby Konsulenttjenester Consultant 05.1995 - 06.2002 Ajilon Substitute Teacher 08.1994 - 07.1995

AWARDS

Episerver Most Valued Professional (EMVP) Expired 2017

Gran School, Oslo

LANGUAGES

FOR FUN

EXCELLENT Norwegian (native), English INTERMEDIATE Bulgarian Spanish, German, French, Japanese BEGINNER

High Valyrian